# **MATTHEW ROGERS**

4737 34th St. Unit #15, San Diego, CA 92116 (916) 952-4662 matthew.shane.rogers@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/matthewsrogers

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Proven leader with seven years of experience in the university and non-profit sectors, with a commitment to growth who is looking for opportunities which help cultivate social impact using technology. Excellent reputation for relationship building and coaching clients into personal, academic, and professional success. Skillful in developing collaborative partnerships with local, university, and international stakeholders to understand success drivers and to coach clients in meeting their contextual goals. Seasoned user success coach, with extensive experience in strategic planning and consulting. I am adaptable in my style and strive to bring a learning perspective and to communicate best practices.

## **EDUCATION**

Coding Bootcamp Full-Stack Developer / Present / University of California San Diego
B.S. Biomedical Engineering / 2007-2012 / California Polytechnic State University San Luis Obispo

## **SKILLS**

- Software: Microsoft Office, Google Apps, Karani(CRM), Active, Mail Chimp, Adobe, WordPress, Drupal, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Communication: Strong skills in verbal, written, and inter-departmental communication and collaboration, vision casting, public speaking and donor/public relations communication and listening.
- Coaching: Expertise in individualized development for 25+ individuals in discovery of and follow through of strategic goals. Excelling at methods including Goal, Reality, Options, Will (GROW) model and Specific, Measurable, Attainable, Realistic, Time Oriented (SMART) goal training and execution.
- Project management: Skilled in creating, managing, and prioritizing multiple quarter to year-long projects, budgets of \$50K+, and personnel to achieve goals.
- Flexibility: Capable of adapting, improvising, problem-solving, and thriving in new situations and/or challenges.
- Cross-cultural: Knowledgeable and thoughtful while learning and interacting within the needs
  of black, Latino, international students, including other diverse populations. Participated in
  over 100+ hours of inter-cultural competency and led two national and international
  trainings.

## **EXPERIENCE**

MAY 2020-Present

Junior Web Developer Intern | EnterTalk Media Inc. | San Diego, CA

• Efficiently created and managed WordPress websites for clients

## JANUARY 2006-2007

iPod Technical Support Agent | Apple Inc. | Elk Grove, CA

• Excelled in customer satisfaction and resolving technical issues while servicing 200+ clients via iPod troubleshooting calls.

#### SEPTEMBER 2009-2012

Audio Visual Technician | Media Distribution Services | San Luis Obispo, CA

• Effectively managed maintenance and service and operation requests of media equipment including repairing AV equipment

## JANUARY 2013-PRESENT

Campus Manager | InterVarsity, USA | Santa Barbara & San Diego, CA

- Cultivated and maintained a fundraising network for 7 years, raising an average of \$60,000 annually with a year over year growth by 3.4%. Nurtured a 150+ donor base with regular and effective communication utilizing CRM software to prioritize phases of donor development.
- Effective strategic planning for growth and improvement of client programs and events, increasing attendance and commitment to service by 20% over 5 years.
- Pioneered innovative marketing strategies to generate interest and visibility via campus-wide outreaches, designing brand websites, sustaining social media and Mailchimp updates with conversion rates.
- Proficient at training clients and colleagues in peer-to-peer leadership to help them address barriers to achieving their goals and innovating for what could change if they followed through.
- Skilled at creating data tracking programs via google sheets and forms and maximizing regular reporting for following up with diverse populations. Supervised teams of 4-20 leaders annually to connect with over 200+ prospective clients.
- Collaborated with other staff in creating, evaluating, and assessing quarterly and yearly team training events and retreats to resource and retain leaders and grow our capacity to assist more clients, ranging from focused 5-person retreats to 100-person conferences.
- Directed two short-term learning exchange teams to collaborate with global partners to expand brand marketing for international partners through interviews, process demonstrations, and user experience analysis.